One
Un
Two
Deux
Three
Trois
What's up buddies?
¿Qué tal amigos?
Here's OscarJark
Habla OscarJark
This is the first of a series of videos
Este es el primero de una serie de videos
In which we'll know the history of Pump it up
Donde conoceremos la historia de la Pump it up
Without further ado, let's start
Sin más preámbulo comencemos
Pump it up is a dance simulator launched by the company Andamiro
Pump it up es un simulador de baile lanzado por la compañía  Andamiro
which has 2 pads with 5 arrows
el cual cuenta con 2 paneles de 5 flechas
In each of them, a screen and speakers
cada uno pantalla y bocinas
But... What does Pump it up mean?
Pero... ¿Qué significa Pump it up?
Is an English expresion used to cheer up people or turn something up
Es una frase en inglés que se utiliza para animar a la gente o para subir el volumen de algo
Therefore It would mean something as "turn it up" or "light it up"
Por lo tanto sería algo como "súbele" o "anímate"
Here J-o teaches us how to use it
Aquí J-lo nos enseña cómo usarla
Let’s get loud Let’s get loud
Let’s get loud
PUMP IT UP!
PUMP IT UP!
and another example
Y otro ejemplo más
Don´t you know? Pump it up? You’ve got to pump it up
Don you know? Pump it up? You’ve got to pump it up
and now let's move on to the dance machine
Y ahora sí vamos a la máquina de baile
Everything started in 1999 in South Korea
Todo comenzó en el año 1999 en Surcorea
when in August came out the first
cuando en agosto salió a la venta la primera
Pump it up which was called  "The first dance floor"
Pump it up a la cual llamaron "The first dance floor"
This PIU had hits relatively recent in the country
Ésta contenía éxitos relativamente recientes en el país
The first game included 15 songs
La primera máquina contenía 15 canciones
which were 1.35 minutes long and 4 Non-Stop on average
de 1.35 minutos aproximadamente y 4 Non-Stop
Remix with about two and a half minutes of duration
Remix de alrededor de dos minutos y medio
Speeds  2x, 4x y 8x were avaliable
Se tenía acceso a las velocidades 2x, 4x y 8x
vanish, random, and non-step too
Además del vanish, random, y el non-step
A drawback is that you could only chose from 4 songs per stage
Lo negativo es que solo podías escoger entre 4 canciones por stage
Evidently the steps were very different from the ones we know now
Evidentemente los pasos eran muy distintos a los que conocemos ahora
Since there were only normal, hard and double difficulties
Ya que solo existían las dificultades normal, hard y doble
the hardest songs from the first  version were Hypnosis and Ignition starts
Las canciones más difíciles de la primera versión eran Hipnosis e Ignition starts
With an "astonishing" hard 7 and 8 respectively
Con un “impactante” hard 7 y 8 respectivamente.
But "nya" if you think about it everyone was learning
Pero ñaa si lo piensas todos estaban aprendiendo
how to play in that moment
a jugar en ese momento
So they didn´t need as hard steps as today
Así que no necesitaban tanta dificultad
the hardest remix was was the "Turbo remix"
En los remix el más difícil fue el turbo remix
In this game the most outstanding songs were: Funky tonight, Black cat
En este juego las canciones que más sobresalieron fueron: Funky tonight, Black cat
Forever love, Cordiality (now known as "Another truth").
Forever love, Cordiality (ahora conocida como Another truth).
There was battle mode in which you had to stomp the steps so your rival imitate them
Existía también el modo battle el cual consistía en pisar los pasos para que tu rival los reproduzca
Here's an example
He aquí un ejemplo
If you notice the players stepped a sequence
Si notas los jugadores pisaban una secuencia
that the rival the opponent had to immitate
que el contrincante en turno tenía que imitar.
When Andamiro realized the pontencial and acceptaion of its videogame
Andamiro al percatarse de la aceptación y potencial de su videojuego
launched  "The Pump it up 2nd ultimate dance floor" only 4 months later
Lanzó The Pump it up 2nd ultimate dance floor tan solo 4 meses después
In which double mode and dupbles were added to
En donde se agregaron más canciones y dobles
the Non-stop remixes, the steps patterns were more diverse
a los nonstop remix, los patrones de pasos fueron más variados
the interface was basicaly the same though
aunque la interfaz es básicamente la misma
Is here where we see  hits such as Final audition house come out
Es aquí donde vemos nacer éxitos como Final audition house
of Banya, group that had an even more important
de Banya, grupo que tuvo una participación aun más
participation  in this machine, giving us the hardest song
importante en esta máquina Regalándonos también la canción más difícil
of the time that was "Extravaganza"
de la época que fue Extravaganza.
Com´back, Tell me tell me
Resaltaron también Com´back,
and Curiosity satanded out as well
Tell me tell me y Curiosity.
There were included 2 songs only avialable untlill the bonus stage
Se incluyeron 2 canciones solo accesibles al bonus stage
Fighting Spirits of H.O.T. and the Non-stop remix 7
Fighting Spirits de H.O.T. y el Non-stop remix 7
We've gotten to May 2000 when Andamiro releases the O.B.G or the OBG In which
Llegamos a Mayo del dos mil cuando andamiro lanza Pump it up the O.B.G o la OBG donde
around 27 new tracks are released including a lot of 90' hits in Korea
se lanzan alrededor de 27 nuevos temas incluyendo muchos hits de los 90 en Corea
that's why the name (Oldies but goodies)
(por eso el nombre de Oldies but goodies)
which would mean something like ¿viejitas pero buenitas?
que sería algo así como ¿viejitas pero buenitas?
In this version existed the need of presenting crazy mode
En esta versión hubo la necesidad de introducir el modo crazy
due to the advances in the player's skill level
ya que los jugadores también mostraban avances en sus niveles
She likes pizza surprised players with an astonishing 230 BPM
She likes pizza sorprendió un impactante 230 de bpm
"an interesting view" was outstanding. Not as the crazy level of Extravaganza though
an interesting view era sobresaliente aunque no como el crazy de Extravaganza
currently single 11, the hardest song in that version
en la actualidad single 11 ¡lo más difícil de la maquina!
The crown speaking of difficulty in the Non-stop remix category
La corona en cuanto a dificultad para los non-stop remix
was for Banya  - Ignition starts, Hypnosis and Extravaganza  remix
Fue para el remix de Banya Ignition starts, Hipnosis y Extravaganza
The most outstanding songs were Caution or Don't Bother Me, We Are, Final Audition 2
Las canciones más sobresalientes fueron Caution o Don't Bother Me, We Are, Final Audition 2
and Turkey march of course.
y por supuesto Turkey march.
Another big improvement was in the BGAs
Otro avance enorme fue en lo referente a BGA’s
or BGA's which stands for background animation
o BGA’s que quiere decir background animation
Because they told stories and they were
ya contaban historias y eran
way better quality wise. Even the non-stop remixes had  their own
de mucho mayor calidad. Incluso los nonstop remix tenían el propio
in contrast with the old remixes videos
en contraste con los videos de las remixes anteriores
which looked way more random and repetitive
que lucen mucho más random y repetitivos.
That's it for this video. See you in the next one
Eso es todo por este vídeo Nos vemos en el siguiente
See ya!.
See ya!.